<!--
  ~ Copyright (C) 2025 tekBlueprint, Sergey Grachev <sergey.grachev@yahoo.com>
  ~
  ~ This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  ~ it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as published by
  ~ the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  ~ (at your option) any later version.
  ~
  ~ This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  ~ but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  ~ MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  ~ GNU Affero General Public License for more details.
  ~
  ~ You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
  ~ along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  -->

<tekKnowledgeTechnology group="arch" artifact="restapi" version="0.1">

    <name>RESTful API</name>
    <tags>restful, api, web services, http, json</tags>
    <website>https://restfulapi.net</website>
    <description>
        REST is an acronym for REpresentational State Transfer and an architectural style for distributed hypermedia systems. Roy Fielding first presented it in 2000 in his famous dissertation. Since
        then, it has become one of the most widely used approaches for building web-based APIs (Application Programming Interfaces).
        REST is not a protocol or a standard, it is an architectural style. During the development phase, API developers can implement REST in a variety of ways.
        Like the other architectural styles, REST also has its guiding principles and constraints. These principles must be satisfied if a service interface is to be referred to as RESTful.
    </description>

    <i18n lang="ru">
        <entry path="description">
            REST — это аббревиатура от REpresentational State Transfer и архитектурный стиль для распределенных гипермедиа-систем. Рой Филдинг впервые представил его в 2000 году в своей знаменитой
            диссертации. С тех пор он стал одним из наиболее широко используемых подходов для создания веб-API (интерфейсов прикладного программирования).
            REST — это не протокол и не стандарт, это архитектурный стиль. На этапе разработки разработчики API могут реализовать REST различными способами.
            Как и другие архитектурные стили, REST также имеет свои руководящие принципы и ограничения. Эти принципы должны быть соблюдены, если интерфейс службы будет называться RESTful.
        </entry>
    </i18n>

</tekKnowledgeTechnology>